# **RILEY SMITH**

Mobile: 480-239-4339 Email: rileylsmith80@gmail.com

#### **OBJECTIVE**

I plan to use my experiences; both as a leader and a team member to attain a coaching position at the high school level. As a student athlete I have discipline, a great work ethic, and understand the importance of working with a team to get great results. I continue to strive to build my skills in preparation for my career.

### ATHLETIC & COACHING EXPERIENCE

**Performance Zone Volleyball Club** 

Gilbert, AZ

**December 2019-Present** 

16's Assistant Coach

Assisting in all facets of club coaching including; practices, drills, lineups, and team building activities.

Park University Gilbert, AZ July 2019-November 2019

Assistant Women's Volleyball Coach

Assisting Clay Webb in the development of the Women's Volleyball Program. I am the acting Head Coach for the Varsity Reserve matches. Within my role I am recruiting for future seasons to help this growing program succeed.

Spiral Volleyball Club Chandler, AZ 2013-2019

Coach & Player

Played Elite Volleyball for three seasons at Spiral; when I was recruited to Community College in the area I became a part-time coach. Served as Head Coach and Assistant Coach of various teams; ages 11 through 17, assisted with summer camps, tryouts, open houses, clinics and private lessons.

South Mountain CC Phoenix, AZ

## Volleyball Player, Student, August 2012-May 2014; Assistant Coach May, 2017-January 2019

Worked with Coach Pat Mooney in an Assistant coach role for two seasons, responsible for diverse tasks, running drills, one on one instruction, team activities and equipment care. Served as site coordinator for AZ Volleyball sanctioned tournaments, opening and closing facility, dealing with team and player/parent issues. During the 2018/19 season I was tasked to focus on coaching setters and designing the offensive plays, I planned and coordinated specialized practices and drills and held film sessions to help teach the athletes how to break down game play. As a Student Athlete, involved in all aspects of the team including communicating events, practice plans etc. I was a team leader both on and off the court.

Each Student Athlete worked to fundraise for the team; Pro-Em was a sponsor of our teams and as such we worked for Pro-Em and many events throughout my two years at SMCC. We preformed many tasks and the funds that would have gone to pay us went directly to the team for uniforms and equipment.

Recruited as a JC transfer, I used my remaining eligibility to complete my Bachelor's Degree and Graduate Degree under my scholarship. I have worked under 4 Assistant Coaches and 2 Head Coaches at my time at

RILEY SMITH Page 2

NMHU and understand the need to embrace change and flexibility. During this time, I have also worked 3 Summer Camps, being placed in charge of the setters and running specific drills.

## **HONORS, AWARDS & CERTIFICATIONS**

Joe Sellah Leadership Award Member – USA Volleyball Association; Certified to work with Youth Volleyball Programs 2013-2014 Academic All American

## **EDUCATION**

M.A., 2017 New Mexico Highlands University Human Sports and Performance-Sports Administration

B.A., 2016 New Mexico Highlands University Psychology Major

A.A., 2014 - South Mountain Community College, Phoenix, Arizona Psychology Major

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

GoDaddy Scottsdale, AZ July 2019-Current

## Website Specialist (Customer Service)

Provides excellent inbound and outbound telephone support for all customers as their initial point of contact. Responsible for answering customer questions and summarizing project requests, which are sent to Web Builders for execution. Ensure clients understand the features and ability of the plan they have purchased outline customer project requests; articulate information between Web Builders and customers to ensure web design is complete and accurate. Accurately complete documentation required after each interaction.

Dream Center Education Holdings, LLC Chandler, AZ May 2018-May 2019
Human Resources Services Representative, Human Resources

Provide front line service support to employees on various HR matters including but not limited to: payroll, benefits, personal info updates, and general policy and procedures information to locations nationwide. Respond to employee inquiries in an accurate and timely manner via chat, email and/or phone. Escalate complex situations to the appropriate person/department. Enter employee related data into the HR information system. Ensures accuracy of data entry through the use of manual and system audit reports. Process PT/adjunct faculty payroll for up to five thousand employees; entered and compiled schedules and pay adjustments for system uploads. Certify proper completion of received HR documents according to stated policies, working with staff to resolve outstanding issues and departmental delivery goals are met. Provide high level of service/support, assists with research issues and troubleshooting as requested.

# Isola Group Chandler, AZ Various School breaks 2015-2016, July 2017-May 2018

# Intern/HR Assistant, Human Resources

Assisted in all facets of the department; accurate data entry of new hires, expense reports and filling. Served as a back-up to the receptionist, and set up employment interviews. Working with the benefits coordinator I was responsible for open enrollment processing manual entry, open enrollment auditing, ACA (Affordable Care Act) reporting and auditing as well as preparation and distribution of 1095-C's. This position required me to learn processes quickly, perform my duties accurately, work with minimal supervision and deal with confidential information.